Guide to the John R. Kiely papers M0907
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
John R. Kiely papers
1945-1956
Department of Special Collections and University Archives
Kiely, John R.
Bechtel Corporation.
Bechtel Power Corporation
M0907
33 Linear Feet (53 boxes)
Project management files, personal project files, and correspondence documenting John Kiely's years as Vice-President of Bechtel Corporation's Power Division.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
Gift of Margaret Lee Kiely, 1996.
Conditions Governing Access
Open for research. Note that material must be requested at least 36 hours in advance of intended use.
Scope and Contents
John Keily was an executive VP and director at Bechtel. He started in paper & pulp with Crown Zellerbach and joined Bechtel during World War II to run Calship in Los Angeles. He led Bechtel's power division during their early atomic energy days, managed Jubail, and later managed many hydroelectric projects in the 1950s. Keily oversaw BART politics in the 1960s, and retired around 1978. Keily passed away in January 1996.
The papers span 1947 through 1952, the period that Keily was the Division Manager of the Power Division of Bechtel Corporation. They are an ideal snapshot of four years in the life of a Power Division executive. A portion deals with his relations up the corporate hierarchy and with his boss Ed Garbarini, while other parts survey the field of power construction. There are also complete papers on a few big projects - the Big Creek hydroelectric plant, Contra Costa oil-fired plant, and Kyrene steam plant. These records give a very complete picture, including material on design decisions, labor relations, environmental reports, cost accounting, insurance, subcontractor monitoring, certification of drawing and construction quality.
Electric power production; Construction projects; Kiely, John R.; Bechtel Corporation.; Bechtel Power Corporation
- Bechtel Corporation--personnel experience records, organization charts, personnel files, Specifications for Big Creek Office Building and Club House (Box 1)
- Bechtel Corporation--salary classifications, overhead costs (Box 2)
- Bechtel Corporation--design specifications, Station P progress reports, Job 1704 Book 1 (Box 3)
- Bechtel Corporation--Job 1704 Books 1-3 (Box 4)
- Bechtel Corporation--Big Creek #4: including weekly cost reports, accounting data, core drilling, equipment catalogues (Box 5)
- Bechtel Corporation--Big Creek #4: including schedules, financial & engineering reports, insurance laboratory tests, estimating data, equipment rental (Box 6)
- Bechtel Corporation--Big Creek #4: including tabulations of construction equipment purchases, miscellaneous construction data, daily force reports, costs (Box 7)
- Bechtel Corporation--Big Creek #4 material file, Florence Lake Dam structural analysis, steam station study for Hawaiian Electric, miscellaneous projects (some bid and lost) (Box 8)
- Bechtel Corporation--miscellaneous projects (some bid & lost) (Box 9)
- Bechtel Corporation--miscellaneous projects (some bid & lost), including Hawaiian Electric, Mammoth Pool Dam Site (Box 10)
- Bechtel Corporation--Salt River Power District, Contra Costa project: including progress charts & reports, schedules, studies, wages & hours, safety (Box 11)
- Bechtel Corporation--Contra Costa: including progress reports & charts, equipment, medical services, organization, wages (Box 12)
- Bechtel Corporation--Big Creek #4 Daily Force Reports (Box 13)
- Bechtel Corporation--Big Creek #4: including insurance & safety, medical facilities, organization, procedures, progress report correspondence, quantity reports, wage & labor relations (Box 14)
- Bechtel Corporation--Big Creek #4: including industrial indemnity reports, specifications & studies (Box 15)
- Bechtel Corporation--Big Creek #4: including specifications, report on powerhouse structure (Box 16)
- Bechtel Corporation--Acres Canadian Bechtel of Churchill Falls progress photos, Big Creek specifications & costs (Box 17)
- Various trade publications; Bechtel Corporation--loose files, Hamilton Falls Power Project report, Sultan River Project Description, Trip Report for S.D. Bechtel and G.P. Schultz-Indonesia, Chino Mine Progress Report, Caroni River Dam (Box 18)
- Various trade publications; California Shipbuilding--Major Facilities; Bechtel Corporation--Manhour Costs & Employment Data, Big Creek photobook (Box 19)
- Bechtel Corporation--Calship Facilities construction costs, Edison Hydro Project, National Labor Agreements, Insurance Manual, Salary Brackets and Classification, Names and Addresses of Directory Personnel; California Shipbuilding Corporation--Production & Cost Trends, Ship Repair Procedure (Box 20)
- Edison News; USMC Cargo Vessels General Info & Instructions for Operating Engineering Systems; Bechtel Corporation--Personnel files (Box 21)
- John Kiely planners, 1949, 1951; trade publications; Engineering Data, TVA; Steam Electric Plant Construction Cost and Annual Production Expenses, 1938-1947; United States Marine Commission, operations and construction manuals; Job 1704-Kyrene Steam Plant Installation Schedules (Box 22)
- Bechtel Corporation-miscellaneous proposed projects, Big Creek Nos. 1 & 2; Acres Canadian Bechtel Churchill Falls-progress photographs, publications, loose files, Policy Board Meeting 9/16/68 (Box 23)
- Acres Canadian Bechtel Churchill Falls-Capital Cost Estimate, Engineering Report, Confidential Info for S.D. Bechtel Jr, Board of Directors tour folder; Job 1704 Labor Cost Reports (Box 24)
- Bechtel Corporation--Churchill Falls; New Don Pedro Project Data & Maps; Power Outlook Reports, 1951 - memoranda by region regarding utility executives' near term building plans (Box 25)
- Bechtel Corporation--Power Outlook Reports, 1951, memoranda regarding utility executives near term building plans; Hydro-Electric Misc. Technical Data; Steam Plants Misc. Technical Data (Box 26)
- Bechtel Corporation--Electrical Power Outlook; Kyrene Steam Plant project files, Job #1789 and 1704 (Box 27)
- Bechtel Corporation--Kyrene Steam Plant project files, Job #1789 and 1704 (Box 28)
- World Energy Conference, Detroit 1974; World Energy Conference VIII, Bucharest, Romania 1971; World Power Conference, Moscow 1968 (Box 29)
- Beaver Awards Dinner, files and Programs (Box 30)
- Beaver Awards Dinner seating lists; Engineers Joint Council; Cooling Water Cost Files (Box 31)
- John Kiely personal business file; Bechtel Corporation--Job 1484, Utah Power & Light (Box 32)
- Bechtel Corporation--Job 1484 files, including budget and progress reports (Box 33)
- World Energy Conference files, including Conservation Commission (Box 34)
- Bechtel Corporation--various project files, including Bougainville Copper, Churchill Falls, James Bay Project, BART (Box 35)
- Bechtel Corporation--Job 1484, Southern California Edison Steam Station, Etiwanda Pipeline (Box 36)
- Bechtel Corporation--Pittsburgh Plant files & photos, Big Creek, miscellaneous photos (Box 37)
- Bechtel Corporation--various project files, Contra Costa (Box 38)
- Bechtel Corporation--Contra Costa, including progress reports, Architecture, Electrical, "Cost of Job" File (Box 39)
- Bechtel Corporation--Contra Costa Construction Reports & Estimating Data (Box 40)
- Bechtel Corporation--Contra Costa Steam Plant (Box 41)
- Bechtel Corporation--Contra Costa Steam Plant, including Progress Reports (Box 42)
- Bechtel Corporation--Contra Costa (Box 43)
- Bechtel Corporation--Big Creek & Contra Costa (Box 44)
- Bechtel Corporation--Big Creek No. 4 (Box 45)
- Bechtel Corporation--Big Creek No. 4 (Box 46)
- John Kiely Personal Correspondence; Bechtel Corporation--Big Creek No. 4 (Box 47)
- Bechtel Corporation--John Kiely correspondences; expense reports; Statistical Information on Corporations (Box 48)
- John Kiely miscellaneous correspondence and dues; Bechtel Corporation--various project files, organization charts (Box 49)
  - Misc. correspondence and dues (Box 49, Folder 1)
  - New construction (personal) (Box 49, Folder 2)
  - Specifications (original) and approval - Big Creek #4 (Box 49, Folder 3)
  - 1488 Contract data - Big Creek #4 (Box 49, Folder 4)
  - Utah Power and Light Company Contract - Job 1484 (Box 49, Folder 5)
  - Job 1861: Maui Electric Co., LTd. - Contract (Box 49, Folder 6)
  - Contract# 1430: Contra Costa - PG&E (Box 49, Folder 7)
  - Contract agreement for Engineering and Construction service (Box 49, Folder 8)
  - Contract: job 1430, Contra Costa (Box 49, Folder 9)
  - Contract: job 1488, Big Creek #4 (Box 49, Folder 10)
  - Contract: job 1304, Edison Substation Project (Box 49, Folder 11)
  - Jobs: bid and lost, power division (Box 49, Folder 12)
  - Three Steam plants, Alaska: E. Ford Richardosn, Whittier, Erelson (Box 49, Folder 13)
  - Power Division Engineering Organization charts (Box 49, Folder 14)
  - A Study of the Pulp and Paper Industry as a potential customer for Engineering and Construction services (Box 49, Folder 15)
  - Korean Steam plant (Box 49, Folder 16)
  - Power Work: foreign countries (Box 49, Folder 17)
  - E.C.A. work (Box 49, Folder 18)
  - Atomic Energy Commission: bids and future (Box 49, Folder 19)
  - Sales Effort and Control Charts (Box 49, Folder 20)
- Bechtel Corporation--typical contracts, Power Division Overhead Labor Distribution, organization charts, miscellaneous photographs (Box 50)
  - Power Division Overhead Budget and Capital Expenditures Committee (Box 50, Folder 1)
  - Typical: contracts, general procedures and specifications, part 1 (Box 50, Folder 2)
  - Typical: contracts, general procedures and specifications, part 2 (Box 50, Folder 3)
  - Organization charts (Box 50, Folder 4)
  - Power division overhead labor distribution: Vernon office, part 1 (Box 50, Folder 5)
  - Power division overhead labor distribution: Vernon office, part 2 (Box 50, Folder 6)
  - Anchorage Diesel Plant: job 1748 (Box 50, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous photographs (Box 50, Folder 8)
- Eagle Mountain Pumping Plant, Colorado River Aqueduct, Metropolitan Water District of Southern California request for bids (Flat-box 51)
- John Kiely ephemera: glass slides, 35 mm negatives, miscellanesous notebooks, check stubs (Box 52)
- Flat Box Items (Flat-box 53)
  - Hydro-Quebec Tower Collapse (Flat-box 53, Folder 1)
  - Property of J.R. Kiely: reports- Millie and Severson, Incorporated (Flat-box 53, Folder 2)
  - Hamilton Falls River Project, Canada: photographs (Flat-box 53, Folder 3)